RITIKA MOZA

UI/UX Front end Developer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

7 years of Industry experience in providing User Interface & User Experience Design and Development with most usable enterprise wide applications. Specialized in web site designing, Front End Development. Professional at creating creative graphics for the mobile and web Applications, Highly creative and multi-talented graphic designer with extensive experience in multimedia, marketing and print design.

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

- Worked as a Web UI Developer in NIIT Limited, Gurugram from June 2016 to January 2020.
- Worked as a Front End Developer in Unique International, New Delhi from 2014 to 2016
- Worked as a Web & Graphic Designer in Delfotech Marketing Solutions 2013 - 2014, New Delhi.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

- Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Applications from IGNOU.
- Bachelor degree in Humanities in May 2011 from Jammu University.
- Passed 12th in 2008 from Jammu Kashmir Board of school Education.
- Passed 10th in 2006 from Jammu Kashmir Board of school Education.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

NIIT LIMITED

- Designing website, banners, video content and other UI/UX related content for the client.
- Advocated web interaction design best practices, with a focus on consistency and usability.
- Closely worked with back-end developers to optimize existing Web technology and create the best possible user experience
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues.
- Identifying innovative ideas and proof of concepts according to project requirements.

Contact:

+91-9013017161

E-mail:

rtkmoza44@gmail.com

Address:

Dwarka, New Delhi

SKILLS:

Web Technologies:

HTML5, XHTML, CSS3, Java Script, jQuery

Frameworks:

Angular, React

Web Platforms:

Magneto, WordPress

Script Editors:

Bracket, Dream weaver

Graphic Tools:

Illustrator, Photoshop, Coral Draw

Video & Sound Editors:

Adobe Premier, Adobe audition

Other:

MS Office, Social Media Marketing, SEO

- Providing guidance and troubleshooting support to clients.
- Designed and developed GUI for applications and modules, using JavaScript
- Live available at https://www.rsjms.com

UNIQUE INTERNATIONAL

- Design web applications, their graphics as per user experience.
- Designs, develops and revamped e-commerce responsive sites for clients.
- Rolling out various graphic architectures.
- Integration of images, icons, banners, audio and other features of the website.
- First point of contact for all designing and UI/UX related queries
- Few notable works like Fejour.com, Garten-decor.com infoholidays.in

DELFOTECH ADVERTISING & MARKETING SOLN.

- Story Boarding: Story scenes were transformed into graphical scenes
- Advertisement creation for the products
- 3D & 2D movie creations
- Few notable works like khabar24x7.com ,sapcent.com ,shaadiyan.com

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION:

- 6 months advance graphics and development course from Indian Institute of Skill Development 2013.
- "Completed front end development Bootcamp" certification in Aug, 2018.
- 2.5 years of diploma in Multimedia Animation (AAASP) from Arena Multimedia in 2009-2011.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

DOB: 05-03-1991

Gender: Female

Marital Status: Single

Father's Name: Lt. Sh. Shadi Lal Moza

Permanent Address: Jammu & Kashmir

Languages Known: English, Hindi, and Kashmiri

I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Ritika Moza